<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Chase Coleman</title>
    <link>http://www.chasegcoleman.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Chase Coleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Chase Coleman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.chasegcoleman.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Economics</title>
      <link>http://www.chasegcoleman.com/project/quantecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.chasegcoleman.com/project/quantecon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;QuantEcon began as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quant-econ.net&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; developed by Tom Sargent and John Stachurski oriented around teaching quantitative economic modeling. As time has passed the project has broadened its scope to, not only teaching, but developing open source computational tools for economics, econometrics, and decision making. The project is currently funded by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sloan.org/&#34;&gt;Alfred P. Sloan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and has non-profit status by being a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.numfocus.org/&#34;&gt;NUMFOCUS&lt;/a&gt; fiscally sponsored project. QuantEcon is currently guided by a steering committee which consists of: Susan Athey, Daisuke Oyama, Matthew McKay, John Stachurski, and Thomas Sargent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on this project you can visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quantecon.org&#34;&gt;QuantEcon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BYU Macro and Computational Laboratory</title>
      <link>http://www.chasegcoleman.com/project/byumcl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 01:14:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.chasegcoleman.com/project/byumcl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BYU Macroeconomics and Computational Laboratory is a collaborative group of undergraduate students and professors at BYU doing research in the field of computational macroeconomics.  We operate under the following set of premises:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bright, motivated undergraduate students can make significant contributions to macroeconomic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To do so, they need appropriate training in numerical tools and economic theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They also need guidance from faculty dedicated to undergraduate mentoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the example of the BYU Math Department&amp;rsquo;s successful IMPACT program, we select a group of well-prepared undergraduate students who have completed the economics core curriculum and who have a solid background in mathematics.  We train these students extensively during Spring Term in an intensive “boot camp” environment where they are a) introduced to a set of useful computational mathematics tools, b) introduced to modern dynamic macroeconomic theory and methods, and c) trained in numerical programming techniques.  During the following academic year students are brought onto faculty-sponsored research projects, usually as full coauthors with the intent of producing a paper ready for submission to peer-reviewed academic journal by the end of the school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in the BYU Macroeconomics and Computational Laboratory as a student from April 2012 to May 2013 and then as a TA from April 2013 to July 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>